all right welcome to our saturday
roundtable
where we talk about our project and then
talk about how we create game b
because none of us need help so who
would like to start
for this week i can start
go ahead ben
so uh i've been working
on reason score project to build mass
agreement
i talked to some uh
video debaters they used to debate on an
app called call out where you'd be able
to do a video debate
when you said hey i'm doing something
that's not video debating but it's kind
of similar
um and i'm willing to have
prizes do a little debate competition
i think everyone skipped over the fact
that it wasn't video debate
because there's three people interested
but
so it might be a rude awakening but a
scheduled a meeting for next week and
we'll see how it goes
uh so that'll be interesting to get some
feedback
um and then i'm working on a portfolio
site for myself because i'm gonna need
to start earning some of that game a
money and
actually have a someone contact me about
a job
it's pretty boring work but pays the
bills
and yeah that's mostly what i've been
working on got oh and then for another
project that i've been working on for
startup
i talked to them about um equity and
some sort of ramen noodle pay
um to survive uh
so um yeah those that's so those are
things i've been working on i'm really
looking forward to seeing
um more of what of what's happening in
wikilection and stuff so
i guess i'll go then um so wiki election
has been going well i uh
stayed after the meeting yesterday with
bentley and radek
and we saw the newer version of the
prototype
um the new i don't know what to call it
thing scoring the scoring matching the
rating system maybe the rating system
yeah you know that that works uh it's
coming along nicely i think at some
point we're gonna have a meeting to go
over the more complex part of it because
we just saw like
the front end how it looks when it's
being used
um but that was cool hopefully we'll see
that live on
the actual live version of the wiki
election prototype soon
um and then after that we'll be doing a
pivot to conferati
where the end goal is still to have wiki
election but conferrati
is sort of the name behind the guess the
overall tech to like
review evidence and summarize it and
that whole thing
um so that has to get proven out before
work election is any use
so work election is definitely still a
thing and is probably one of
the main reasons to do conferrati but
there's that reason for the
pivot and the confront is also the one
where um
people will be reviewing organizations
instead of just
people which also seems very timely so
uh
i've been working on that and the design
is sort of how that's slightly different
and
the next steps for when uh radek is
has like just pushed this newest version
of the election and we can start on
comparative so
that's where i'm at
all right is that leaves me is the next
person the last one
um i have solution raising as well as
this new mlm idea that i'm working on
solution raising we the week before last
we canceled the relationship one because
i wasn't really in the mood no one
showed up so i quit before anyone else
came
and so we held it this week and it was
actually a really good solution raising
um coming up with some powerful ideas on
how we could could help people with
dating
and this next week we're going to be
doing a solution raising on solution
raising itself which i've been meaning
to do for a while
um and so people who have been to at
least one solution raising coming in
saying of course what it's like
what they would love it to be like and
then what we could do
to get to ten thousand people hundred
thousand dollars or i don't know how i'm
exactly gonna
get awarded it but but to do that and
the mlm is partly to get to the ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars
um with the mlm idea with
all of my ideas i feel like
they're powerful and big and yet i'm
never able to do it by myself
i'm never able even like the mlm i'm
like i can't really make even like a
landing page or even like i don't even
know what steps to go through to do that
like i don't know
there's a um either like ripping a page
in half
and then how many times do you rip in
half till there's nothing you can't
write as infinite or fold it in half and
then how long does it take to reach to
the to the moon
that's what i feel like like it's like
my brain keeps filling in the gaps be
like oh could you handle this oh could
you handle this but it's like it's never
quite and it's not supposed to be like
it's not supposed to be that i can do it
by myself it's supposed to be
almost from day one that i have other
people doing it with me but i don't know
how to
get those that person those people and
so i'm just kind of sitting with that
currently springs into existence
so that is where where i where i
currently am
yeah i certainly know that feeling um
although what's interesting though is
you i
think you kind of started all this with
the together tech idea
and now we're building it even though
you've kind of moved on
for is your main focus uh so maybe it's
just a matter of time
but yeah yeah no and i i honor that as
well like
part of it's just the feeling that that
it's constantly i'll be like i'm in this
alone i'm like i have to save it all by
myself i'm like you could have said that
a year and a bit ago you can't say that
anymore like
there are so many people but there's
still that like
how does even if somebody wanted to come
support me i don't even know how
right like it's it's and i feel like
most of the world has
an understand like they know what they
need
or are able to do it themselves and they
need to outsource it because they don't
have enough
time in the day but they could still do
the thing right they could write the
email they just choose not to and choose
to officers
because i can't i can't even really
explain it to the other person of like
why i can't try to be like this because
it's like well if you can save the
entire world with a global cooperative
or whatever it is we're doing
why can't you do this thing and it's
hard to be like
because i can't this is what i can do i
can show up and have a conversation on
video
so i need other people to show up and
have the conversation on video and then
do the other stuff around it
that needs to get done right both the
tasks and then actually doing the tasks
and i'm willing to take on anything i
can but
just that right it feels like the
universe just keeps ripping my paper in
half it's like okay you're closer
you're so close you're so close
because there is something very powerful
in this mlm idea where it does
handle recruitment it handles a lot of
the stuff that we've been talking about
for the last
last year um that all of our projects
need right the people the resources it's
just
how to get it together and out into the
world so that we can find the first 10
people
and that who can recruit 100 and recruit
the thousands
and putting that together in a way that
it makes sense to people as opposed to
my brain who likes the math and
i like the pyramid math i don't like it
happening in the world
and all its horrificness but it's like
how we use the worst business practice
to be
to be the best
but that was definitely my check-in we
can continue on with
or we're gonna end up chatting about i
do feel like i wanted to mention that um
wikilection feels a little more
important now that not that it wasn't
always but now that ruth bader ginsburg
died
there's something about like
we need to stop leaving it up to our
government officials to solve [ __ ]
because they're not going to and like
the idea that yeah there's five people
in the supreme court they're gonna have
a big impact not just on the united
states but the whole world
but can that be what we deal with right
like why if we had the full picture
if we had wikilection five years ago i
don't know if we'd ever have kavanagh i
don't know if we'd have trump elect i
don't know
i don't know whether trump and hillary
would have been the ones from not that
long ago but
yeah and i mean i the end goal for me is
still
wicked election conference is sort of a
step to there
but sort of in walking through it like i
don't think book election is trustworthy
until khan ferrari is done
because until until then people are like
so why do i trust you versus all the
other sources like how is this actually
different
that makes the evidence a little bit
more transparent hopefully but
without actually summarizing and going
through the evidence and showing that i
think that's the
the important step and we'll actually
still be working on book election at the
same time
actually mentioned some people in poland
that were unhappy with
a certain i think
political group and some people so he
was going to possibly approach them to
see if they wanted to use
work election to sort of i guess help
paint that picture so
i'm going to be looking at doing that
once the
the prototype is up and online and ready
to actually get sort of
start to summarize politicians
i don't know if any of us have a hot
seat topic or
need
i guess we don't have radix so we and it
would be confusing if we worked on the
values
[Music]
i guess we're all kind of building our
projects i don't know maybe this is the
time also to see if anyone
needs any other assistance
um
on anything i was thinking you know i
you know
i could use people that are willing to
debate a topic uh
using a tool rather than just verbally
or
written in a facebook post or twitter
uh but it you know it would take some
time
uh but it'd be stretched out over weeks
it'd be like you know an hour every
couple days or something
or an hour a week so it would be a lot
of work
um and it'd be helpful if it's the topic
that they were actually
passionate about and believed in and we
could find someone on the other side
that they
believed in as well uh it's you know you
can debate
um something you don't believe but i
think
you end up going down rabbit holes that
um and kind of misrepresenting the other
side
um because you're not living with it
in your mind so that's kind of less
valuable than a true believer
i've also thought about i'm back on
maybe doing some prototypes
for my portfolio site and one of them is
uh the ideological turing test i haven't
figured out a name for it
uh not that i necessarily need a name
and that's a name but it doesn't mean
much to people when you say
it but uh the concept is that you go to
the site and there's kind of
two actions you can take one is you
could
it'll show up two um
articles short form articles about a
topic
and then you try and decide which person
is uh
has wrote that article that doesn't
believe
in what they're saying so they believe
the opposite
and one of those two articles one is
written by a true believer and one is
written by the opposite
and you're trying to pick out which two
and so the goal of the other side is
that you're trying to write you take
a topic you write two articles one for
the side you believe in one side you
don't
and your goal is to have it to where the
other side can't tell
that you don't believe in what you're
saying so you're able to accurately
represent their side
uh and that's called the ideological
turing test
i like that a lot that sounds
interesting yeah so that wouldn't be too
big of a project i think so it'd be like
a little portfolio site that would
that also kind of help diffuse
and have this kind of work together
because if you can if you can really
phrase the other side really well then
then that that kind of discourages or
encourages you know really thinking
through what's going on
so it'd be a fun little side project
if i was in any way capable of writing
i'd be down for it
i'm gonna ramble on five minutes on the
other side i can do mask no mask i can
do
i can usually play devil's advocate for
the other side there's very few things i
can't but
in in a real way like i can see it from
their side and be like this is what this
is and this is what this
is but i'm not writing it out come to
think of it there's no reason why
i mean the the concept works for other
regards of the medium
so maybe allowing video would be a way
to
make it even more interesting i'm not
gonna host video on my site so they'd
have to record a youtube video and then
post it to the site but
or two youtube videos but be really
confusing to my audience bentley you're
gonna be like
anti-black lives matter auntie mask and
he's like
like yeah let's figure this out but you
can do unless
that could end up being pretty hilarious
if if a challenge
like that actually blew up or like a
bunch of people like wait they're saying
what now
no it's for this challenge you
understand
yeah for sure like the wrong one but
it's also because you're
even something like anti-black lives
matter or or
you know the pro-trump
i don't know if i would be able to do
pro-trump in an unbelievable way except
written maybe even though i can't write
it but like once i start
smirking maybe
that was except that it becomes obvious
especially on video it's like it's hard
to keep a straight face and it's hard to
like it's it's i think it'd be easier to
write it out and have people convinced
that you're
on that side there's other ones though
that i could do more
convincingly like mask no mask i get it
from the other side but i think
any time where you're not just like
putting your idea out there and having
to actually perform it i mean
that's an extra talent then because you
have to not only
create the words to say but then perform
it in a believable wave rest
as you said something you don't believe
so i think that would be more
interesting to watch
personally but it would also be way
harder yeah yeah
it might be something i could add later
text is pretty easy
also like having random strangers watch
it right because i mean
if people know me they're gonna know
what's they're gonna know i'm left
they're gonna know i'm anti-capitalist
they're gonna know all these things
whereas
um like i can argue capitalism i could
do that
and not but like nobody who knows me
would believe it
but that's the they don't know me right
they're just watching like yes this side
and the side
yeah yeah yeah getting a poll of
semi-random people would be
an important part of it but that
project's been done
several times several teachers and
colleges have
assigned that to their students and and
had
another class or another group of people
um read them not knowing which side they
were on and
trying to find it so i thought it'd be
an interesting thing to make a site
you and you get side by side or whatever
right you're not trying to pick
all of the game yeah yeah just between
two
and you know one's real one's fake think
of calling it find the fake
from the perspective of the people that
are coming in
i don't know if that domain's available
probably just do it on my domain first
see if it works
interesting because i was also thinking
of a few different like
sort of fake like intentionally fake
news type tools
where like you would go and take um a
current news story
and like have people sort of highlight
things that could be you know swapped
out or ad-libbed
and then sort of create like a news
ad-libs and then be like hey which one
of these articles is true right
and take something like about
donald trump but then slightly tweak it
so instead it's about obama
and then see like so is this true and
what what and what do you think about it
oh you think it's good obama did that
okay it was actually trump do you do you
still think it's good
and did you just sort of have that test
i saw like have
different tools to sort of test that i
think that might be an interesting
thing that sort of still fits in the
same vein in my mind
where yours is is a lot more i think um
like actually sort of testing the
creation of content if you believe it
like i
think that's one of the more interesting
parts
but also requires more work because it's
more uh like actually
the writing of two essays i think yeah
it's it's difficult to have that be like
the best part and then have other small
bits and pieces
yeah there's i think there's a couple
sites where they they kind of put you
through a little
news quiz like that but it would be
interesting
to have it to where people write it or
an ad libs thing and
have more content and make it more of a
that would be very interesting
i'm not going to use the same basic tech
in theory
yeah i mean in there like this
could did definitely warrant having its
own thing but it also seems like
um something that you could end up
i'm not sure that this would kill the
purpose or not i think it would still be
useful
um to have something like khan ferrari
review how accurate each article is
right because like if you're just
going through and taking you're talking
news points like or taking your you know
if you like msnbc and so you're right
you write your
the piece you agree with just full of
msnb msnbc talking points and then the
thing against it you just fill with fox
news talking points
well they're both probably bs then
yeah so which what like that have it be
which one do you believe okay now here's
the how true each one is
yeah and then it's it it would be cool
if i could actually
tell you that as you're writing it so
it's like hey
cool thing uh 90 of this is wrong
try again oh this is the one i believe
oh
yeah another um interesting thing about
the site is you could also get a public
rating so you'd have a
domain where you go to and they could
say okay here's here's
don't believe anything this person says
they're really good at life
right that's a good point uh here's a
page on
on wiki election because they're also a
politician yeah
but yeah being able to pass the test and
and kind of show it
but would be interesting is i don't
think you could ever
for the work people couldn't ever like
have that article
there's no there'd be no way to link to
the to what you wrote
maybe um so no one could ever
kind of see what you wrote intentionally
because they would go to the site and it
would just pop up two
pieces of text now that was losing the
text would be more anonymous than
video video would would not so maybe
video wouldn't work
kind of in the short term at least i
think
video could still end up working as long
as like i think to your point it
wouldn't be a video
that you that you could just go and pull
up it would need to be like
okay now the context of this video is
one of these is fake
and it would sort of be like you know
you need to be on the back end
and one of the things that i'll end up
needing is people who actually are good
at creating that kind of fake content
because that is kind of an important
part of converati is the
it is that test is like the having
intentionally fake content
that skews one way or the other and see
if you spot that as fake and see if you
spot that is skewed
or see if you skew it in one way over
the other like with you know
the trump obama example well if it's
wrong
then it's still wrong if the other
person did it if it's right then it's
still right if the other person
did it so why is your opinion changing
yeah
yeah it'd be interesting to to have that
as best i have a question about
which i don't know so
like trump there's those um the new
recording of him coming out from right
before kovit where he's finding out
about it and
that he is giving it more of you know
it's like this is a big deal
but then of course all of his talk in
the public about that stuff was like
whatever it's gonna
even still it's just gonna go away it's
gonna randomly go away
and i don't think he's that eloquent of
a speaker but the world seems to think
he's an eloquent speaker
and so there's a certain i'm the
opposite of that partly because i can
see both sides right and so they're both
actually trying to get out at the same
time
that there is the ability to speak but
there's also
like are you actually consistent in
because i don't have a problem if he
went from no it's not a big deal it's a
big deal to not a big deal it's that
when he was saying it wasn't a big deal
he knew it was a big deal and he's lying
right he doesn't actually like his he's
not necessarily going back and forth
just his talking points are going back
and forth versus
somebody who can see more of a big
picture sounds like they're
more wishy-washy and flippy floppy when
they're not they can just see the full
big picture right there i'm not going
from pro
from like this pandemic's huge and every
and the government should lock us all
down and back and forth it's like no i
can see
how our governments are going to
overstretch and i know science so i know
that a virus
is going to act in the way it acts and
we don't have a say in it right that
that's a very different standpoint
than fear-mongering and or
yeah anyway i don't even know what i'm
asking you to measure but measure that
well i think in if you talk about the
actual
politicians i think there was something
in wikileaks and yeah that
ajo you were gonna kind of measure
people
flip-flopping is a bad term because
we want people to be able to change
their minds but yeah consistent
flip-flopping
back and forth would be bad i think
step one there is like hillary does have
it right yeah
i think our first step is just having a
timeline
so you can see exactly what happened
when okay here's a news conference of
trump saying this
here's when the recording happened
here's the next news conference
dude like does something make sense
there we're like oh he said this and
then
okay there is some consistency there or
is it a complete two-sided like in the
public heat of this and the private here
this oh and here's two more private
conversations in here
like to start to be able to spot that
trend and then also to be able to fact
check and say like okay this is actually
what we knew it
at that time how does that fit it
because a big part of it is we're always
seeing slices and it's kind of up to
each person to figure out like
okay bentley here's some news go and
figure out how that fits into everything
else
you know about all the people involved
yeah you know you have to have the the
beautiful mind strings on the wall
be able to follow every news story and
people just don't pay that much
attention yeah
yeah and with trump it's an interesting
thing because
a lot of his supporters don't expect him
to be
i can't remember the term there was
someone was saying he's
honest but not accurate like he says
what he feels
and that's what people would like to see
they want to see passion they want to
see
that kind of thing
um he also pisses off the people that
they want to piss off
right yeah right so those those
statements are
are having the intended effect right
right
and then some people that support them
just really like
anarchism so uh you know having
throwing a monkey wrench in the works is
uh entertaining
yeah uh and then then i have some good
friends that
really like the policies that he ends up
passing
um so they don't really care about what
he says
yeah i mean i i yeah i fully understand
why people
could still support him because it's
been like
you ever been in a room where an alarm
is going off and you have to stay in
there and after like 10 minutes you stop
hearing the alarm
i think that's where the world is at
with donald trump yeah i mean jubilee no
because
of your whole half death thing but uh
late i think with a lot of it i there
hasn't been a single day in the last
four years where we haven't all heard
the name donald trump
and it hasn't been like blah hair on
fire the world is ending
and it's like guys just pick one in 10
stories to freak out about
it it's not every i remember like two
months in there was some huge story
about like
melania's dress color or something i'm
like wow we're here already huh
like this is important news yeah
yeah above my head that's your topic
sure has anyone heard of um topia
t-o-p-i-a it's in beta at the moment
raymond sent me a link and then i forgot
to look at it and then i right before
i went to he's going live i don't i
don't quite understand because he gave a
12-hour window
but anyway it looks like it's a place to
hang out kind of like a discord but
i don't know i'm gonna go check his out
during that 12-hour period and maybe
sign up for one for um
core solution reasoning so what's the
actual domain because it's not just
topia right i mean topia dot
topia.io when i'm on is topia
welcome dot opia dot io backslash
pricing
but the free version has 10 people
maximum capacity and i don't know
whether that's 10 people in per time i
don't literally nothing about it besides
the fact that raymond said it was cool
and
wanted to go hang out in it and i'm
going to go hang on
with whoever else is there he was very
particular about no politics
how is that going to go raymond
probably pretty well he's pretty good at
holding his face for that probably
yeah there's just like no
no politics in this world like what are
we talking about then because anything
becomes politics right
even without ever mentioning a
politician it's like oh
especially yeah i can't really tell they
they're
saying it's kind of like i mean the
catchphrase sounds like a social media
but further down their description
sounds more like
video comforting yeah there was
something on it that was also you could
like video chat with people in your area
and whether that meant you're like on
and therefore you can get connected
i know a lot of those services that have
been like that in the past it just ends
up being
naked people on like a lot of penis pics
like it's like come on man like like
chat roulette and stuff it was like
let's see if we can not get a naked
human on the other
on the other side but to be able to do
that right where you can just connect
with someone in chat
is would be awesome
kind of like writing it running into
people on the street but
hey have you heard about my lord and
savior anti-capitalism can we chat
yeah the content on their site makes it
seem a bit like
i don't know for a better chat at work
we were trying to find like an online
water cooler
right and we found something that ended
up being like this weird it was like an
online office map where you could like
join a room
and then that's what like you joined the
text and audio chat for that room so
that you could have like different
that was weird yeah there's one where
you actually
have little avatars you're walking
around um
and then uh i know a guy who does kiko
chat and he has
you can click on the rooms and kind of
go into them
hey reddick but yeah i guess topia is in
a
an online event organization
tool
[Music]
so it's funny they it's a it's a
well-made site it just
doesn't seem to quite i
a lot of startups and stuff you come up
with the way i don't really
know what you're doing here
i don't know if i'm going there or not
customize page they have
a short video being used and yeah it
really
just seems like
a video chat where you've also got an
avatar that walks around a map for some
reason
oh so it is that same somewhere thing i
mean having people walk around a map
is useful because
in video you have to be very intentional
about
who you're going to group off with and
like breakouts or something like that
but being able to just kind of walk up
to a conversation and have the volume
get a little louder and then walk over
to another conversation without like
popping in and out um right is a neat
thing um i haven't played with it a lot
we just need to all go into the r and b
virtual reality yeah we'll just skip
that step and get
the matrix jack so we can just
so right do you want to give a project
update on anything or
have any topics or things you need help
with
that's a standing um
project update is not much happened i
mean a few updates but
about from that not
as as planned so it's been quiet
for too long
i do still think one of the most useful
it's again
no one in the game b space has yet taken
this project on besides
literally just having a list of them but
i want to know not just in the game b
space but like every time someone comes
out with tech what does it do how does
it compare to everything else who owns
it
is it good or not right like does it
like why are there all end pricing
definitely pricing as well what do you
get for the free version what do you get
for the increased version
i mean with all of these things i think
they're much more powerful if we own
them together because we can improve on
them instead of needing to create an
alternative that's that's and for some
reason it's popped into my head
because i talk about mac a lot mountain
equipment co-op and co-ops that they're
getting sold to an american
non-non-cooperative but then the members
i didn't even hear about it as a member
and other members are like no don't sell
it i'm like
[Music]
are you gonna shop there
what's the end i didn't even know you
could sell a cooperative i'm like wait
how did how can you do that without the
members saying okay but then what's the
alternative bankruptcy like i
anyway it's throwing me through the loop
and that's right yeah it'd be
interesting to see the legal
yeah who gets the money from the sale
i think it just goes to paying off debt
and then it's like there is a profit
interesting whoever owns the brand
because everything is a brand so
probably uh
even a cooperative is maybe sometimes
its main
value is not the people involved but the
people who signed the
status and uh like the agreement
usually it's just a few people so i
would imagine
in this case uh as well
it's like mech mount equipment co-op or
they can take the c
out like no it's just mec we're not even
going to say the full just the amount of
equipment corporation still let me see
i don't know it depends on their by-laws
on how that all happens it could be done
several ways
it's like the difference the
juxtaposition between people and mlms
who are in no way business owners but
think they are so they have this weird
loyalty to both the company and the
product
and the community that like doesn't make
sense in a capitalist world where you're
like okay
you don't feel that way about google or
mcdonald's or you don't think they're
there for your benefit but somehow this
company
existed just so you can make an income
and just so you can have this a
world-changing product
whereas a cooperative is like actually
that like you actually all
own it together but because of what met
like there's no
there's no loyalty right it's like yes i
really want this thing that we all own
to have
to have really ethical practices but
then i'm not shopping there
and where like the mlms can make their
stuff as expensive as possible they're
like oh no there's a lineup when it
first comes out with something yeah
cause you're the customer
the owners are like it's like if which
is what i'm trying to
create the mlm slash cooperative that
takes the best of both but
i can't change the psyche of people like
why do you think you
why i don't understand why you think
this for-profit company is good and then
this other one
gets sold and by the wayside and
yeah i don't know if that's marketing
just
you know for-profit tends to have more
cash for marketing
or if it's some other bit of our own
psyche
kind of like when you get something for
free you don't respect it as well
um i'm in this accelerator it's one for
under underestimated founders and then
there's another one one of the workers
there
well the staff came from a women's
uh founders thing they said they weren't
charging for the accelerator
for the women's um and they had like 40
people interested but then it put her
down to 10 and people just kind of
flaked out
so i don't know if charging a fee a high
fee
up front um there's a lot of businesses
where they say we made more money when
we raised our prices
didn't change the product didn't change
anything it's just that perception of
value
yeah i had that exact same experience i
used to do
business consulting and found that
nobody would ever make a change a free
consultant
right because i was just like oh this
person needs help and i
you know in some cases i knew them in
some cases i just knew
the industry so i gave them you know
experience i
i saw one person actually make a change
and then i started charging
all of a sudden people started to make
changes because they're like i'm paying
for this i'd better do it
so yeah there's absolutely a thing where
when you charge for it you you do value
it more
so maybe yeah or you're gonna pay for it
only if you value it right like i know
i'm signing up for a ton of free
five-day course here five-day course
there and it's like i go in and the
person annoys me and it's like no peace
out
if i'd paid 100 bucks for it i wouldn't
you know i wouldn't i wouldn't pay a
hundred bucks to sit because i wouldn't
know if it's good quality
but part of it is like right well i set
up for three i can't keep up with three
of them
and this person annoys me this person
you know
doesn't have good content in this so i
have ended up following through on some
of them
and strangely the one that i liked is
the higher price point one
for her other content and she's the one
i did pay and i've yet to do the course
ten dollars for one of her other courses
because it was also a good deal so the
free one was good and i'm like okay i'll
pay ten dollars for your course
but most of our courses are in the
thousands of dollars
yeah there's a lot of psychology about
perception of value
that you know i i don't know i mean
if you're doing a cooperative i wonder
if it would be good but
yeah you know i have i mean we want to
make sure it's accessible to everyone
but just making sure that it survives
and it also can fund other things
the question is do we have the prices
seem extravagant
and then based on some other way we
either have scholarships or some sort of
metric that
that allows to make it affordable for
everyone
um i don't know if we want to have
everyone submit their tax forms
so we know how much money they make but
um
some sort of way of handling that um it
might be
i guess just being super transparent and
then letting people say
right like here's the three product
lines here's the price
breakdown here's what each thing does
right so like okay
oh the first difference between the mid
price and the high priced is you know
the high price has absolutely zero
slavery so you decide
right the middle priced one maybe it's
still better than walmart right so it's
like yeah there's still some slavery
involved in parts of these
the supply chain here is where but you
know it's a quarter of normal
okay and then that one there's nothing
but but it's four times the price
so buy whichever one you want but the
whole point is you have to be able to
compete
just in the marketplace that item has to
be good
and like it can be you know probably a
tiebreaker or like a bit of a
differentiator to say you know here's
the zero slavery line but as mec found
out
if you don't actually compete in the
marketplace if you ignore that part
you're probably not
going to be successful
i was just going to say if um there is
something psychological about
having to pay for uh stuff and
uh it's not pain itself it's the
exchange of stuff it's something more
and then again
there is this um idea of sometimes uh
sacrifice as being the exactly the thing
that
uh in mythology there's uh
every mythology has something like uh
a quest type of thing where
some god or some some
super bean needs to uh
make a great sacrifice in order to get
something so there is
there's nothing deep uh here but it made
me think of
um yeah when you are paying for
something especially if uh the price
is like exactly in the spot where it
feels like
uh i can still afford it and it's
uh big enough for me to actually feel
that i'm
i've paid for something so the correct
correct
question to ask people is how much money
would you
like to give us in order to be
like bound to us
yeah that's interesting i hadn't thought
of that that um
part of increasing satisfaction might be
charging more money
and then because people feel sad more
satisfied with the product
and with using it and the company that
gives it to them
yeah in value of the item you still
can't charge ten thousand dollars for a
bag of chips
but you also probably should charge five
dollars for a car so
like i think there's some expensive
ranges for each like and that's part of
mech's
business like um van city which is a
credit union
all credit unions are cooperatives as
far as i know
uh that you pay you used to be fifty
dollars five dollars and sits in a
member share and you use the bank
account or you don't so you're
but like mec is the same you're paying
five dollars for a share
you don't even necessarily understand
what a cooperative is to shop there they
just make
like get you to sign up for a five
dollar share and then you're a lifetime
member
and there's something about that where
it's like okay it's not costco where
you're paying the same
fee every year so you're like wait if i
pay five bucks a year
i might be more willing to shop at mec
over the next one
because i'm reminded every year but then
at the same time maybe then i would have
shopped there and i'm not going to shop
there because i'm not going to pay five
bucks extra
to shop there this time if i'm only
coming once a year so
there's incentive both ways but anyway
that's part of the mlm
idea of paying 25 bucks a month and
having scholarship
is that it's enough that most people can
it's low enough that most people can
afford it but it's still an amount
that's bigger than netflix it's bigger
than right
you can just add that to the pool and
feel good about it
but also is it bringing you value are
you here to
pull your money and save the world right
to be able to do actual
powerful things with that and because
it's coming out monthly it's like right
people might fall off and they're
actually the perfect people to fall off
right if they are like yeah this isn't
worth it for me
great awesome
so jubilee what are your next steps in
that
project with the mlm are you still just
figuring it out
well i have it i have the basic product
figured out and the basic um
mlm thing figured out i just need
someone to like
put it down in a way that can explain it
to other people
yeah so you need someone to have you
recorded videos on all of that
no because it's not something i'm
especially for the mlm itself and the
product
actually um aren't something i really
want to release on my youtube channel so
i want someone else to steal the idea
and co-opt it for gaming right
like or even to co-opt it for their game
b
you know honestly and i'm like oh this
is interesting there's some rivalry in
me
like i don't want someone to steal the
product because the product itself
is the community and there isn't a
community yet
right so anyone creating that whatever
the community is that starts
starting with whatever 10 people are
going to create the culture are going to
create
anyway yeah i have the product and more
or less and the um
structure and that's part of it is that
the
solution raising was going to be the
product or something very similar
but solution raising doesn't appeal to a
broad base
it appeals to a very specific group of
people like everyone
seems to want the ideas that come out of
solution raising to be made but they
don't necessarily want to participate in
solution reasons
i think there's something very similar
to that that is about your own life that
everyone almost everyone does want to
participate in
or at least the people who are like the
self-help community and the spiritual
community
and stuff want to participate in but
then it's not very
it's game b but not game b right it's
like sneaky you don't need to know game
b to participate in it and creating
lives that work for us helps us
then be more free to to
work on projects together right working
on projects together like the the bigger
we grow the better the product gets
because the bigger the community grows
and the more
we have in the catalog at the same time
starting from a place that isn't very
game b
but it's game b but your name is saying
it's you don't need to know what omni
winner is you don't know who anti roblox
is to come and create a life that works
for you
but the people i want to retire the
people i want to take out of game a and
put into game b
are game b people who aren't necessarily
the people who are going to come and be
like yeah i'd like to sit around and
talk about my health
and my my finances and my relationships
to improve them and so part of it's
separating them out so that it's like
okay what people want to create
the recruitment structure and the
retirous structure
and focus on that and who wants to
participate in the product
right and those people might overlap and
they also might not overlap but it's
like these people talking about creating
this
in a way that would work for them would
work for the most of their friends and
family
so that it can be something that they
can invite anyone to
and it will be powerful and so you
really need someone who
either is an author can take your
thoughts and
write it up or uh marketing
yeah i need both of those things yeah
yeah what i really need for solution
raising or for this
is somebody who can bring people to it
right like for the mlm i don't think i
would have a problem recruiting 10
people
in the game b space i don't think that
would be the problem it's what am i
recruiting them to i don't want to have
another
um what is the word what was true
what did i create after solution crazy
process raising
where it was just very confused like
what are we doing and every time raymond
would just be like oh yeah
i think they're already doing what
you're doing i'm like they're in no way
doing what i'm doing it was like very
because i tried to just throw people
together and be like we're gonna create
this so there has to be
that foundation of here's the structure
you're coming on board for
here's what is somewhat concrete and
here's what is gray area we're all going
to decide together
and here's the product i'm fully the
product i'm not tied to but it has to be
something that
is has these characteristics right and
it's
what i've come up with i think is a good
starting place for one to then
work through having it and seeing can we
incorporate the people who participate
in the product in making the product
better in a way that's not just at the
end of a class how could we improve
right where it's like no
what worked for you what because one if
it's a six week course one of those
courses is how was this for you
let's talk about the whole course in
general and getting
the feedback from that what would have
made it even better
what did you love what did you hate what
would make this more powerful
so yeah i think kind of like you need a
someone to help you build a pitch deck
for those first
so those first 10 people that come in
understand it
well yep um
yeah otherwise i which was so happy when
i first created it i have a slightly
different conversation with everyone and
they
change it which is powerful and awesome
that's what happened when i first had
the id and then i talked to mark and i
was like okay and then it altered it
enough
but then do i go to talk to the first
person right i'm in the stage where it's
no longer altering
and so yeah getting that more concrete
here's what it is and here's what's
great area what we're going to decide
together
if no one minds i think for the last two
months i'd like to
angle to the wikilection project and
maybe
um i mean maybe not go full technical
but
um get an idea on
because i guess i i keep falling back on
me wanting to build this matchmaking
thing but i also don't want to duplicate
the work you've done radic
[Music]
but also if it if it doesn't quite fit
my vision i might
so i guess if we could
um see how aligned we are
um i know i i i think you
implemented it your intent was to
implement
pretty close to the way i described it
like you're riffing on my idea
anyways i don't know if you have
anything you want to say about that or
uh not sure i was um
the logical conclusion and uh logical
next step
for the work that started was to
make it more flexible in terms of what
kind of data what kind of what
types of entities can exist in the
system and
then i read your google doc and it
seemed very similar so
uh yeah i think i followed that line of
thought since then
so yes so what i think i would
like to do is i want to spread the idea
out
slightly larger than wik election and
conference and also include kind of the
other ideas so i was thinking about
putting together a single demo page that
does maybe not even have a back end
hooked to it
but has some sample data and then lets
you like
add some stuff to it just to kind of
prototype
and also some alternate front ends to
what what you've done
um uh but i you know if i'm gonna
i don't know if i want to go ahead and
use the data structures you've already
built
or just go off on my own or what but i
guess i'd need to see
some json or some something
on how he did it which i guess i could
go to that site and
it's not going to be um
i can commit everything right now or i
can just clean it up a bit and then
commit everything
uh right after um i don't believe
things don't need to be clean because
it's a prototype so i
so i would prefer you go ahead and put
it up there so you don't
get distracted um although i was just
looking in github do i
have access to the github i think i sent
you an invitation
but maybe not yeah you know it's funny
it's so hard to find things in github
for some reason i don't know why
the home page it's like they list some
of my stuff it's like
oh thank you more button maybe if i read
the directions
the problem is it has all the stuff i'm
working on and everything i've ever
followed
here we go right so it's just this big
spaghetti mess of like where's
my stuff where's the other stuff uh
yeah yeah so if you don't mind just
throwing it up there and i can have a
look and see whether
um i agree with all the micro decisions
you had to make
just so i'm not needlessly reinventing
the wheel
yeah the problem is as uh as the usual
problem in those cases is that um
starting with
uh just a few assumptions
it left me with too many uh
kind of decisions to uh to be made
and um it's a bit too
sketchy so in some places in the older
parts of the code it's it looks
different in the newer
uh it's slightly different so um
i'll commit it you will see it and
and if you want to point me to one or
two files that you think
have the newer ideas helpful
but yeah don't feel pressure to make it
look nice
i just it'd be nice for me to get
feeling i won't
um judge it too harshly being a
prototype
uh oh
um
i'm trying to think there's any other
topics we want to go over
maybe we should require someone to be in
the hot seat every week rotate it
because we're all about telling people
what to do right
okay i committed everything to um
my part but then
oh where did it go oops
because i mean i know ah
36 seconds ago so i probably if you see
the
collection so it might be the
even the right place for the code to go
so
yeah okay do you see it
entity.js something like this
yes yes yes yes yes that's the okay
i'll take a look
appreciate you um uh
doing all that work yes
and yeah hopefully and by the way um
it seems like uh totally seems like this
is
something worth doing um i mean of
course it's something we're doing
uh generally but uh this is something i
also
like um it's something that i
could use myself and i this is something
i would personally like to see
um finally being out there
and doing the thing as as discussed
yesterday
so i think it would also help you know
jubilee even
wanted it earlier today when she said
you know something that
tells me which projects are good and i
mean there's other data like who did it
and when
and stuff but that whether it's good and
why is it good and whether it's what i
need
um yeah that that this is the base
infrastructure for that so it's funny
because
every every day i see one or two people
say they wish they had this
it's it's it sounds like fun
foundational like there's wikis
there's blogs and then there's this
right yeah no it's it's something that
does come up
cool quite a bit and all the different
parts to it like the adding one the
searching for it across
different entities that now have the
same topic
in mind one of the nice things about the
wiki election conference sort of
version of this is there will end up
being some variation like for example
the scores that you might use to like
end up summarizing a person would be
slightly different than the squares for
organization
and the scores that you'd be reviewing
content are going to be completely
different
than the scores for a person or you know
the author
um so there that will hopefully help
sort of hash it out a bit and help
show hey here's this one tool using this
thing in three or four different ways
but like here here and here on these
pages these scores are all that thing
and then this matching spot over here is
that same thing
um because i think one of the my
experiences with tools like this
is like it took us all a while to sort
of understand
exactly what it was doing to be like
okay i can see how that's useful it's
hard to explain that
as opposed to like go look on this site
see all the scoring it's that
yeah i think when we have a few examples
and most people won't care because they
want the specific use case right so they
don't care that it's a
that's a no code creator of that um
but yeah for the for the people that
might use it
like if jubilee wanted one of these that
she could spin it up quickly
um without too much configuration
although i don't know if
however if you can figure out how to get
it so i can do it
you're in a whole other level but yeah
someone else
yeah something where you don't have to
have any technical skills beyond like
you know if you've used excel to balance
your bank account then
you should be able to do it um
it's interesting to think that um
there's there's going to be like flat
field
it's not going to be flat but a graph of
entities and connections and and stuff
but then what is personalized about it
is
different scholars and uh how
yeah different scores as scores
being mattering
differently to different people and
then i wonder if there's if it's
possible to have some
some sort of arithmetic going on
on different types of scores between
like if there's any relation between for
example the way you
uh score organization
and like political party that's kind of
the same type of
entity but then you have products and
they have different type of scores
but uh i wonder if
there would be some statistical
some patterns in how people
of course will be how people judge
things according to themselves and how
the scores
are
i was going with this summer well like
in
in some countries a five means you did
okay
in some countries of two and a half
means you're okay so
scores have different meanings different
people but also to your earlier point
i i think yeah eventually we'll be like
you know if this company
has slave labor and this company has
uh doesn't bad environmental practices
then maybe those two should multiply
in how bad quote bad the company is
so being able to actually write out
formulas like you did in excel
um might be something that some people
would use or having those pre-built and
then people could choose them
yeah that would be interesting so like
if you can say that you care about
environmentalism you know and
animal rights and and everything and
then you want to evaluate a company or a
product
we're like okay but if i don't care
about i don't know
a certain thing and they don't do well
there yeah it's fine that still doesn't
get affected into their score
but then you know if they're bad at
environmentalism and animal rights and
slavery
and i have those as my personal sort of
things that i care about that any
company that has all three
there is some sort of a multiplicative
you're like oh
that company's really bad don't deal
with them there's the alternative where
they're kind of bad in slavery and bad
for animal rights but like
they're better on the other things all
right i guess that's an improvement
yeah it's a personal set of modifiers
what happens now with legislation is uh
the legislation has set of scores and
uh they get applied to
the person to the voter to the
politician
uh by transformation
uh and transformation of if the person
voted
yes and if the person voted no
different scores are applied to the
person so
it's a very rudimentary form of
transformation but
in case of personal uh preferences
yeah every user should be able to say i
care about environment very much but i
don't care about
some other factor and then um
the user would perhaps see
modified scores uh everywhere it's like
the
lenses having lenses through which to
look at
things personalized that would be
something
oh yeah next stage and a library of
scoring mechanisms so like even like an
organization like if you follow
i don't know what's in what's a
non-profit
animal rights organizat like the aspca
or something like that
um you know
and then you can see how their ratings
applied to the companies they're
interested in so you don't have to do
the math if you don't want to
but right yeah and nonprofits are a
great example where that's also a new
set of criteria that maybe only apply to
them
like what percentage of their proceeds
actually go towards their state of
purpose
yeah which like you wouldn't really do
that for google because their state of
purpose is profit
so it goes towards profit it doesn't
really matter the same as like
if i want to give money to an animal
rights organization and there's these
five
a how those organizations operate but
then b what percentage does each of them
actually give
to their state of purpose if one gives
fifteen percent one gives eighty-five
percent
well i don't what i'm doing is i see a
head slowly sneak into rodex frame
we probably didn't need to shut it down
[Music]
it was a lot of fun thank you everybody
it's cool next week on friday where
we're talking about values
on our board meeting and then this time
next week for round tables feel free to
come so it's not our same four faces
you're not the same four
projects again and again you can be in
the hot seat we will focus on you for
the hour
maybe that's why no one shows up because
they think that the first time
also thinking if no one else has hot
seat next week maybe i'll be in the hot
seat we can do
rather than i will actually we'll try to
solve our our life
problems we'll do wish obstacle together
if no one else wants to
have a hot seat after we do yeah
it's kind of like round table for your
personal life instead of for your
project where are you where do you want
to get to what's stopping you yeah
yeah all right in broadcast bye-bye
people